Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Glen Dell Papers, 1969-1989
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Glen Dell papers 1969-1989
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company.
4.5 linear feet Extent: 3,000 Items
Established in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Glen Dell served 1984-1986 as an executive in finance and administration with JWT Group. Collection spans the years 1969-1989 and includes financial reports, correspondence, acquisition and investment information, as well as materials on JWT's subsidiaries and international operations (including Canada, China, Europe and South Africa). Companies referenced in the papers include Carl Byoir, Gray and Company, Hill & Knowlton, Lord Geller Federico & Einstein, and Ogilvy & Mather. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
RL.00680
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company Glen Dell Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1993.
Biographical Note
Chronology List
1935 Born
1957 BA, Amherst College
1957-1971 Financial Analyst and Treasurer, General Electric Corporation
1958 Military service, U.S. Army Reserve
1971-1984 Treasurer, Group Executive, Vice President, International Paper Company.
1985-1987 Executive Vice President--Finance and Administration and Chief Financial Officer, JWT Group
1992-1997 President, Investors Management Services
1995- Board of Directors, Forbes Magazine
1998-2007 Partner, MapleWood Equity Partners PL
2011 Director, Verisk Analytics
Collection Overview
Collection spans the years 1969-1989 and includes financial reports, correspondence, acquisition and investment information, as well as materials on JWT's subsidiaries and international operations (including Canada, China, Europe and South Africa). Companies referenced in the papers include Carl Byoir, Gray and Company, Hill & Knowlton, Lord Geller Federico & Einstein, and Ogilvy & Mather.
Collection Arrangement
Arranged into two series: General Files and International Operations.
Subject Headings
Dell, Glen A.; J. Walter Thompson Company; Carl Byoir & Associates; Gray and Company; Hill and Knowlton, Inc.; Ogilvy & Mather; Advertising -- Canada; Advertising -- United States; Advertising agencies -- Canada; Advertising agencies -- China; Advertising agencies -- Europe; Advertising agencies -- South Africa; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Advertising executives -- United States; Subsidiary corporations; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following JWT collection in the Hartman Center
Corporate Documentation
Herbert Eames Papers
Penney Burnett Papers
Treasurer's Office Records
Detailed Description of Collection
- General Files, 1969-1986 and undated
  - Board of Directors Meeting, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Capital charge, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Carl Byoir acquisition, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Chicago Office, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Emery Worldwide, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Expense account policy, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Finance chronological files, 1985-1986 Oct. (Box 1)
  - Finance chronological files, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Finance chronological files, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Finance--full year results, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Finance--JWT Group vs. Ogilvy Group and Interpublic, Competitor Highlights, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Gray & Company acquisition, 1984-1986 (Box 3)
  - Gray & Company acquisition, 1984-1986 (Box 4)
  - Gray/Hill & Knowlton merger, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Gray merger--Project Neutral, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Hill & Knowlton, 1981-1986 (Box 4)
  - Hill & Knowlton, 1981-1986 (Box 5)
  - International Paper Company, 1986 (Box 5)
  - International transfer cost reports, 1985 (Box 5)
  - J. Walter Thompson Fund, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Job description, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Joseph O'Donnell remarks to Board of Directors, 1986 (Box 5)
  - JWT Corporate Committee, 1986 (Box 5)
  - JWT Group finance manual, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Jwt Group incentive compensation plans, 1985 (Box 5)
  - JWT Operations Review of Selected Accounting and Administrative Areas, 1985 (Box 5)
  - JWT Retirement Program and Trust Agreement, 1985 (Box 5)
  - JWT U.S. Employees' Payroll-Based Stock Ownership Plan and Trust Agreement, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - Lord Geller Federico & Einstein, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Management Information Services (MIS), 1984-1986 (Box 6)
  - Management performance evaluation, undated (Box 6)
  - Margins, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Marketing plan for 1985-1987, 1984 (Box 6)
  - MRB Group (London), 1986 (Box 6)
  - Office automation, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Office Finance Manager, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Performance Incentive Program (PIP), 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Planning cycle, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Public relations, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Spot buying, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Spot system, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Stock incentive plans, 1969-1981 (Box 6)
  - Stock options, 1980-1986 (Box 6)
  - Strategic Plan for the Years 1986-1988, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Strategic planning process, 1985-1987 (Box 7)
  - Succession planning, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Take-over, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Tampa Office relocation, 1986-1987 (Box 7)
  - Tax review, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Thompson Achievement Awards Program (TAAP), 1983-1986 (Box 7)
  - Thompson Achievement Awards Program (TAAP), 1983-1986 (Box 8)
  - Thompson Incentive Plan (TIP), undated (Box 8)
  - Thompson Plan, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Thompson Recruitment, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Thompson Trust, 1986 (Box 8)
  - Three-Year plans, 1985-1989 (Box 8)
  - Treasury Department, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Victor Gutierrez, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
- International Operations, 1979-1989
  - Asia/Pacific, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Australia, 1982-1986 (Box 8)
  - Australia, 1982-1986 (Box 9)
  - Belgium (Brussels), 1982-1987 (Box 9)
  - Brazil, 1985 (Box 9)
  - Canada, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - China--Citibank Introduction to Investment in China, undated (Box 9)
  - China--memoranda, 1985 (Box 9)
  - China--Review of advertising market, 1985 (Box 9)
  - Denmark (Copenhagen), 1986 (Box 9)
  - Dubai, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - France, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Greece, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Hong Kong, 1985 (Box 10)
  - India, 1985 (Box 10)
  - Italy (Milan), 1984-1986 (Box 10)
  - Japan, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - MERAC (Middle East Research and Consulting), 1986-1990 (Box 10)
  - Multinational, 1983-1986 (Box 10)
  - Netherlands (Amsterdam), 1985 (Box 10)
  - New Zealand, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Philippines, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - South Africa, 1979-1989 (Box 10)
  - South Africa, 1979-1989 (Box 11)
  - South Africa--Divestment (publication), 1985 June (Box 11)
  - South Korea, 1985 (Box 11)
  - Taiwan, 1986 (Box 11)
  - Thailand (Bangkok), 1985-1986 (Box 11)
  - United Kingdom, 1985-1986 (Box 11)